<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on DataLab</title>
    <link>http://de.ufpb.br/datalab/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on DataLab</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} [DataLab](http://de.ufpb.br/datalab/)</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="http://de.ufpb.br/datalab/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://de.ufpb.br/datalab/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://de.ufpb.br/datalab/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://de.ufpb.br/datalab/authors/marcelo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://de.ufpb.br/datalab/authors/marcelo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-md&#34;&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: justify;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marcelo R. P. Ferreira&lt;/strong&gt; earned his Ph.D. degree in Computer Science in 2013 from &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.cin.ufpe.br/&#34;&gt;Center of Informatics&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ufpe.br/&#34;&gt;Federal University of Pernambuco&lt;/a&gt;, Brazil. He earned both, his B.Sc. and M.Sc. degrees in Statistics in 2004 and 2007, respectively, from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ufpe.br/de/&#34;&gt;Department of Statistics&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ufpe.br/&#34;&gt;Federal University of Pernambuco&lt;/a&gt;. Since december 2008, he takes part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ufpb.br/de/&#34;&gt;Department of Statistics&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ufpb.br/&#34;&gt;Federal University of Paraiba&lt;/a&gt;, Brazil, where he is today an Adjunct Professor. From october 2014 to september 2015 he had a pos-doc position at &lt;a href=&#34;https://costalab.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;RWTH Aachen University&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Germany, developing research activities applying machine learning methods to DNA methylation data to predict biological age and to classify mesenchymal stromal cells. His research interests are Data Science, Machine Learning and Computational Statistics, including Clustering methods, Kernel-based methods, Pattern Recognition, Bootstrap, Non-parametric methods, Monte Carlo methods and Symbolic Data Analysis. He has authored scientific papers in international journals and conferences and he has also served as a reviewer for many scientific journals. He is involved in undergraduate activities teaching courses such as Computational Statistics, Multivariate Analysis, Stochastic Processes and Machine Learning as well as supervising students. He is also involved in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ppgmmc.ci.ufpb.br/&#34;&gt;Graduate Program in Mathematical and Computational Modelling&lt;/a&gt;, at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ufpb.br/&#34;&gt;Federal University of Paraiba&lt;/a&gt;, and in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ufpe.br/ppge&#34;&gt;Graduate Program in Statistics&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ufpe.br/&#34;&gt;Federal University of Pernambuco&lt;/a&gt;, where he teachs courses and supervise graduate students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
